<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Musings: A Blog on Musings</title>
    <link>https://blog.ethanwilliams.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Musings: A Blog on Musings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Ethan Williams</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 16:31:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.ethanwilliams.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading 03: Hackers and Painters</title>
      <link>https://blog.ethanwilliams.me/posts/hackers/reading03-hackers-and-painters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 23:06:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ethanwilliams.me/posts/hackers/reading03-hackers-and-painters/</guid>
      <description>Paul Graham writes that hackers are creators, makers more similar to artists than to engineers. He goes so far as to say that the term &amp;ldquo;software engineering&amp;rdquo; is misleading, that hackers should be less concerned with how to do something than what to do. This is a silly distinction: great hacks often don&amp;rsquo;t do completely new things, they do something that has already been done, but in a novel way. Hackers should very much be concerned with how things are done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading 01: Hardware Hackers</title>
      <link>https://blog.ethanwilliams.me/posts/hackers/reading01-hardware-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 18:50:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ethanwilliams.me/posts/hackers/reading01-hardware-hackers/</guid>
      <description>The hardware hackers of 1970s California (what would ultimately become Silicon Valley) thought that it was vital to spread computing to the masses, rejecting the ivory tower of MIT&amp;rsquo;s AI lab. It was this attitude that eventually led to the creation of the first microcomputers—computers that could fit in your living room, not just in university labs or corporate offices. Computers like the Altair 8800 and the Apple II were inconceivable to the giants of computing: IBM, HP, and the like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading 00: True Hackers</title>
      <link>https://blog.ethanwilliams.me/posts/hackers/reading00-true-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 16:12:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ethanwilliams.me/posts/hackers/reading00-true-hackers/</guid>
      <description>Stephen Levy writes that the &amp;ldquo;true hackers&amp;rdquo; at MIT in the fifties and sixties were primarily identified by following a shared hacker ethic:
 Access to computers—and anything which might teach you something about the way the world works—should be unlimited and total. Always yield to the Hands-On Imperative! All information should be free. Mistrust authority—promote decentralization. Hackers should be judged by their hacking, not criteria such as degrees, age, race, or position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, World!</title>
      <link>https://blog.ethanwilliams.me/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 15:46:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ethanwilliams.me/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my new blog. I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to set this up for quite a while now, but never really got around to it. I was finally given some incentive when I started a class called Hackers in the Bazaar, which required a blog to post responses to class readings (those responses can be found here).
That said, I hope to use this blog for much more than just assigned posts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>